-- Usagi Drop Episode 10 -
What's wrong? Did you bite your tongue?
No...
My tooth feels loose.
Stop touching it!
What should I do?
It's probably a permanent tooth growing in. Just leave it alone.
Should I make your rice into porridge?
No, I'll be fine if I eat slowly.
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
Culture
Festival
Daikichi!
Hey.
What is it?
That's my drawing!
Kaga  Rin
Rin-chan, does your dad always come to pick you up?
Yeah, but he's not my dad.
Huh? He's not?
Great drawing.
Hey, hey!
Rin-chan's the best at drawing in our B-Class!
Really?
I bet you could become a manga artist!
What? No way!
Yes, you can!
Papa!
Come here!
Sorry I'm late.
This guy is her dad? He looks like a model.
He's so handsome!
I like him!
Sayaka-chan's dad is the same age as you Daikichi, thirty-one.
Really?!
Is that so?
That's a pleasant coincidence.
My dad's a model!
Whoa!
Come on, Sayaka!
I did a little when I was younger.
I feel like I've seen you in my company's catalog.
Oh, really?
Sorry, but if you don't mind,
could you tell me your company's name?
Oh, that must be me!
I'm indebted to your company!
He sure is chirpy.
I'm a manager at my agency now.
Really?
That seems like a waste of your talents.
I never knew how long I had to work until or when my next paycheck would come,
so when my daughter was born, I stopped right then and there.
Oh.
Meanwhile, I was getting drunk and whining about work every night.
Hey, Micchan!
Oh, Nabe-chin! It's been a while.
He was in school with me.
We're both from the neighborhood.
He's got a boy in A-Class.
This is Daikichi-san, Rin-chan's father.
He's the same age as us.
Really? Nice to meet you.
You too.
These guys do everything for their kids.
Daikichi!
I'm a butcher, by the way.
I've got a shop at the corner of the shopping mall.
Oh, Rin and I always eat croquettes there.
Really? That's great!
I do too!
I know!
Looks like I've made some new friends.
I feel like my life here is much more open.
Hey there.
Hello!
It got cold all of sudden, didn't it?
It did. The kids are already in the gym.
I hope they have their jackets on.
Yeah.
Nitani
Kouki
Wow, his drawing's amazing!
You think so?
Well, it looks like he really thought it out.
Umm, all the kids are in the gym already.
What?! Really?!
Shoot! Sensei's gonna be mad at me!
Boys are hopeless.
So cute! How old is she?
Almost ten months.
Babies are so cute!
This brings back memories!
And then my kid got the flu last week.
Really? That's awful.
Is it that time of the year?
They have to rest for two days even if the fever goes down, right?
Or it'll spread.
Yeah, but I sent mine to school as soon as the fever dropped.
Well, it's understandable.
You wouldn't want to lose your job.
Plus, since he felt better, the virus must have been weakened.
Exactly.
Besides, even if he did infect someone, no one would know it was him.
Wanna leave?
I actually understood where those mothers were coming from,
which makes me feel even more down.
She had a point about losing her job.
Yeah, that's true.
Whenever the weather turns cold, I lose my grip on things.
But Kouki just...
Put on your pajamas!
But when winter fades away and spring comes, I can start breathing easily.
Daikichi!
Daikichi, I'm getting my knapsack, so wait here!
How dumb are you two?!
Kouki, your nose!
I told you to wear your jackets in the gym! It's cold in there!
And don't run in the hallways!
Okay!
I just said don't run!
Kouki's teeth are already growing in, right?
Yes, but because we live in an apartment building,
we can't throw his teeth onto the roof for good luck.
He doesn't really listen to what I say anymore.
Well, I can relate to him.
I would wear the bare minimum.
I would sprint down stairs two steps at a time.
I would finish my lunch and a glass of milk without stopping to breathe.
It doesn't feel right warning kids not to do the same things I used to do.
Did you really do all of that, Daikichi-san?
I think that's pretty common for boys.
Although I don't think of Kouki as just some random kid.
I'm sorry.
It's just that if you were once like that,
then I can rest easy a little.
What are you doing? Walk with Kouki.
No!
Then let's split into a boy's team and a girl's team.
Isn't Rin-chan's face a little flushed?
I think she has a fever.
It might go up.
She's way more flushed than usual!
She doesn't have the flu.
Please have all those at home
wear masks for the time being.
Okay.
That's good, right?
Yeah!
Huh?
You're done already?
Yeah, my throat doesn't feel good.
The doctor said it's the stomach bug, so don't force yourself to eat.
I don't feel...
Rin!
I'll get the wash basin!
Rin-chan has a what?!
Call an ambulance right now!
Well, I already took her to a doctor and got medicine,
but she won't take it!
She doesn't look well and her fever keeps rising.
You didn't make her wear a jacket, did you?
That doesn't matter now!
Did you try mixing the medicine into juice?
You used to drink it right away if it was mixed into something sweet.
I'll try.
Thanks, Mom.
Won't you take just a sip?
It's sweet.
Here, just one sip.
Daikichi.
I'm sorry for coming this early.
How's Rin-chan feeling?
Oh, sorry!
Can we see her?
Oh, sure.
Daikichi, what's up with your hair?
She doesn't have the flu, but still...
go watch some TV, Kouki.
'Kay.
And keep it down!
She fell asleep just before you came.
Her fever keeps rising and she can't sleep that well.
She's not sweating at all either.
Can she keep liquids down?
I know I was supposed to at least give her a sports drink,
but she won't drink or eat anything.
What am I supposed to do?
What is it?
You can't lose focus!
As the adult, you have to stay calm and tell her it's going to be alright.
It's not easy. I've never seen Rin like this before.
Don't think like that! You can do it!
When a child is in really bad shape,
they need someone to stick by their side.
As long as you're beside her, Rin-chan will be fine.
Rin-chan.
Kouki-kun's mom.
Your throat must be dry.
Would you like some ice?
Better?
It feels nice.
Rin, you're awake?!
Sorry, I was in the bathroom.
Daikichi-san!
Oh, sorry.
You can have some more ice in a little bit.
Your stomach won't like it if you have all of it at once.
Okay.
And there's something sweet and
delicious waiting for you in the refrigerator.
Okay.
Sorry. You'll be late for work, won't you?
Rin-chan's really trying her best.
As long as you're beside her, she'll be fine.
Right. Thank you for everything.
Thank you too, Kouki.
Yup.
Sorry, but I'll probably have to take tomorrow off as well.
If you need me, just call.
Okay!
Sorry for troubling you.
What are you talking about?
Just leave things here to me!
Thank you.
Think you can eat a little?
Yeah.
You can eat all the sweet food you want when you have a cold.
I'll have it later.
You'll feel much better once you get some sleep.
Why'd it have to be Rin?
If I'd gotten it instead, none of this would have happened.
Damn it...
Damn it!
Who is it?
Daikichi, open up!
Kouki!
How are you feeling, Rin-chan?
Does it still feel bad anywhere?
I'm okay.
I'll make you some yummy rice porridge now, okay?
Her fever's been rising since noon.
Don't worry.
Even normal temperatures are lower in the morning and higher after noon.
But hers was over 39 degrees just now.
Now, put this in the pot.
Okay.
Daikichi...
Water...
It looks great.
I made enough for you too.
Daikichi, Rin said she wants water!
Okay!
Kouki, stay in this room so you don't get sick too, okay?
I don't care if I get sick.
You will if you actually do!
Thank you.
Thank you, Kouki-kun.
Rin can really relax when you're around, Kouki.
Okay.
Okay Rin-chan, try eating this.
You'll like it. Kouki eats it too when he's sick.
It's a special porridge that makes you better!
Kouki-kun has it too?
That's right.
Anytime he eats this, he feels better right away.
I like it!
Daikichi.
Rin, you're better already?
Yeah!
I feel fine.
I'm hungry.
Could you say thanks to your mom for helping us out the other day?
Huh?
When she took care of Rin.
Can I come home with you guys?
Again?!
Your mom's the only one who's allowed to take you home!
But she's at home sleeping with a cold.
What?! Seriously?!